博士日志
Doctor's log.
今天是在波托贝罗炼狱的第243天
It's day 243 in this... Portobello purgatory.
我唯一的伙伴是一块"我叫石头"的石头
My only companion is a rock I named stone.
问题是, 我在跟谁讲我的这些事?
The question is, for whom am I narrating this?
看来我成了荒诞派对的主角
It seems I've become a featured player in the theater of the absurd.
被那只可怜的蓝色啮齿动物(索尼克)困在这个鬼地方
Marooned in deep space by that wretched blue rodent.
但这一切都还好, 多亏了这和谐的氛围和我超群的智商,
But it's all good, thanks to a breathable atmosphere and my supreme intellect,
正与唯一一位精明的竞争对手较量
Sharpened against the only competitor savvy enough to bring it.
(蘑菇菌"D4"开局)
我一直在努力让蘑菇菌成为首选功能性饮料之…
I've been striving to make fungi into a functional drink of choice...
蘑菇咖啡
Mushroom coffee.
用有限的…
With limited...
有限的
Limited...
直至成功
Success.
但今天, 第243天,
But today, day 243,
一天天的努力有了新得转机…
Has brought a new optimism to my most pressing endeavor...
我的发明能将我从这颗行星踢到另一颗行星(我终于能回地球了)
Planetus exodus to returnicus and kick blue butticus.
如果我的计算无误,
If my calculations are correct,
没有"如果", 而是一定会…
And there's no reason to say "if" because they always are...
这根羽毛笔将是能量得关键.
This quill is going to power my masterpiece.
现在点燃这根"蜡烛"…
Let's light this candle...
看看谁来"敲门"
And see who comes a-knockin'.
嗨!!!
Greetings!
克拉图·巴拉达·尼克托(一首歌的歌名)
Klaatu barada nikto.
特工石头? 就是现在
Agent stone? Now!
谢了, 石头
Thank you, stone.
是时候向这片"狗屎"蘑菇星球说再见了!
It's time to say goodbye to this piece-of-shiitake planet!
这东西你从哪儿弄来的?
Where did you get that?
一个来自地球的可怕的蓝色家伙身上
From a little blue menace on the planet called earth.
我很乐意为你指路
I'd be happy to show you the way.
《刺猬索尼克2》
警察还跟着我们
They're still on us.
这能让他们减速
This'll slow 'em down.
小心. 打扰一下. 抱歉. 来了哦
Watch out. Excuse me. Pardon me. Coming through.
晚上好, 先生们, 介意我开车吗
Good evening, gentlemen. Mind if I drive?
最好系好安全带
Better buckle up.
在后面怎么样啊?
How we doing back there?
现在往这边拐
And now this way.
噢, 抱歉, 我不知道胶带还贴着
I'm sorry. I don't speak duct tape.
-你到底在干什么? -不要害怕, 公民
- What the heck are you? - Fear not, citizen.
我是你最崇拜的英雄, 也是你最需要的英雄
I am the hero you need and the hero you deserve.
蓝色的黎明驱逐了黑暗的…
The blue dawn that banishes the darkest...
天哪!
Holy crap!
别担心没人会受伤的
Don't worry. Nobody's gonna get hurt.
- 那是什么东西? -炸弹, 炸弹
- What are those? - Bombs. Bombs.
它们是炸弹! 那些是炸弹!
They're bombs! Those are bombs!
放轻松啦! 这玩意儿都没亮灯
Relax. They're not even lit.
我再说一遍, 没人会…(受伤)
So I'll say again, nobody's gonna get...
我错了! 我们要完蛋了!
I was wrong! We're all gonna die!
你为啥不减速?
Why aren't you slowing down?
这确实需要踩刹车(脚太短)
That would require brakes.
好烫脚, 热, 热, 热! 烫, 烫, 烫!
It's hot. Hot, hot, hot! Hot, hot, hot!
你丫为啥不让警察来处理?
Why don't you just let the police handle this?
因为这不是英雄们所做的事情
Because that's not what heroes do.
非常感谢你, 请不要鼓掌.
Thank you very much. Please hold your applause.
你听到了吗? 还有一枚炸弹
Do you hear that? There's one bomb left.
- 你检查过座位下面吗? -我当然查过座位下面了!
- Did you check under the seat? - Of course I checked under the seat!
你真是太菜了!
You are terrible at this!
你知道吗?
You know what?
你这消极的态度很影响周围的人.
Your negative attitude is not helping anyone.
它就在你这后面尖尖的东西里!
It's in your spiky things!
怪不得我一直找不到!
I can never find anything in here.
把它从市中心抽走!
Drained it from downtown!
看见了吧! 我告诉过你没人会受伤的
See? I told you nobody would get hurt.
噢, 果汁店
Holy sherbet!
哦, 你好呀
Oh, hello.
不要惊慌, 这只是一次演习
Don't panic. This is only a drill.
-过来 - 不用谢我公民们
- Come here! - No need to thank me, citizens.
在整个晚上的工作中…
All in a night's work for...
蓝色正义!
Blue justice!
你是个可怕的英雄!
You're a terrible hero!
-早上好, 韦德! -早上好, 索尼克!
-Morning, Wade! - Morning, Sonic!
早上好, 青山!
Good morning, green hills!
不会吧
Come on.
索尼克
Sonic.
我想你了, 长爪(索尼克1中养育它的人)
I miss you, longclaw.
我要让你感到骄傲.
I'm trying to make you proud.
现在闭上眼休息一下.
And now for a little shut-eye.
奥兹, 早上好!
Ozzy, morning breath!
索尼克  你还在床上吗?
Sonic. Are you still in bed?
你应该见见汤姆, 知道吗?
You're supposed to meet Tom, remember?
好哒, 好哒, 我起来了!
All right, all right, I'm up! I'm up.
多么美好的一天
What a day.
谢谢你出来陪我, 伙计
Thanks for coming out, bud.
我觉得你和我最近在一起的时间不太多.
I feel like you and me, we haven't had much time together lately.
你钓得怎么样? 上钩了吗?
How's it going over there? You getting any bites?
我不会游泳! 帮帮我
I can't swim! Help!
如果我死了, 千万别去我房间里窥探我的隐私!
If I die, don't look in my closet!
嘿, 嘿, 很好, 你没事的, 来吧
Hey, hey, you're good. You're all right. Come on.
-好冷!  - 好了, 好了, 没事了.
- It's freezing. - All right, okay. Take it easy.
你没事吧
You're good. Okay.
刚刚你钓鱼睡觉, 还掉到了水里…
But now that you've had a nap and a bath...
对了, 其实我昨晚去你房间给你带了些新的漫画…发现…
I went up to your room last night to bring you some new comics and...
哇, 哇, 哇, 停在那儿别动
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Stop right there.
是我就不会再靠近了
I wouldn't come any closer,
因为我吃了太多带辣椒的热狗
Because this little hedgehog had way too many chili dogs.
噢不, 噢不
Oh, no. Oh, no.
我很难受, 快受不了了, 快走开!
I'm so embarrassed. Get out of here quick!
哦, 不, 我的屁又要来了了!
Oh, no, here comes another one!
快去吧快去忙你自己事
Go. Now. Save yourself.
哇, 哇, 哇, 停在那儿别动
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Stop right there.
是我就不会再靠近了
I wouldn't come any closer,
因为我吃了太多带辣椒的热狗
Because this little hedgehog had way too many chili dogs.
噢不, 噢不
Oh, no. Oh, no.
我很难受, 快受不了了, 快走开!
I'm so embarrassed. Get out of here...
我就知道, 我应该用真正的屁
I knew I should've used real farts.
-我们要这样多少次? -什么
-How many times are we gonna do this? - What?
难道放掉抢劫犯, 什么也不做? 好像是抢的十亿来着
Cast your line and not catch anything? Seems like a billion.
我想你知道我在说什么
I think you know what I'm talking about.
撒谎骗人, 还偷偷溜出去
The lying. The sneaking out.
然后假装自己是"蝙蝠侠"那样的人
The pretending to be Batman.
-"蓝色正义"这不挺酷的商标吗? - 别讲那些你真的太鲁莽了
- Blue justice, trademark pending. - Whatever. You're being reckless.
别说这个了
Not this conversation again.
嘿我也不想说这
Hey. It's no fun for me, either.
但如果你继续不负责任, 我们会继续谈下去
But if you keep being irresponsible, we're gonna keep having this conversation.
我有我自己的权力怎么叫不负责任?
How is it irresponsible to use my powers?
索尼克, 你摧毁了整个街区!
Sonic, you destroyed an entire city block!
那个街区已经乱七八糟了 谁在乎呢?
That block was already messed up. Who cares?
听着 我阻止了一次抢劫 我是个英雄
Look, I stopped a robbery. I was a hero.
不 你把人们置于危险之中 而这不是英雄所做的
No, you put people in danger and that's not what a hero does.
你是我的好朋友
You're supposed to be my friend.
而不是我老爸
Stop trying to be my dad.
我能照顾好自己
I can take care of myself.
索尼克, 仅仅照顾好自己不是成为英雄的全部元素
Sonic, taking care of yourself is not what being a hero's all about.
而是要敢于为他人承担责任
It's about taking responsibility for other people.
现在, 我不管你想不想听, 但你还是个孩子
And right now, whether you want to hear this or not, you are still just a kid.
在你准备好成为大英雄之前, 你还有很多事情要做
You got some more growing up to do before you're ready to be the big hero.
但我相信你一定可以
But trust me when I tell you,
总有一天你的力量会被认可的
There will come a time when your powers will be needed.
你不能去主宰那一刻
But you don't choose that moment.
而是那一刻终究会降临在你身上的
That moment chooses you.
看看你
Look at you.
看这儿, 我都起鸡皮疙瘩了
Look at that. I just got goose bumps.
等等, 你说的这些是搬奥普拉的吗?
Wait a second. Did you steal that from Oprah?
不, 伙计, 这是瓦乔夫斯基家族的名言
No, sir. That is a wachowski family special.
是来自我爸爸, 也在这条船上, 也在这个湖面上
Came from my dad, in this very boat, on this very lake.
他总是引导我走正确的路
He would always try and steer me in the right direction.
这就是玛蒂和我一直想告诉你的话
And that's what maddie and I have always tried to do with you.
所以, 在你重任将至那一刻之前
So, until your moment arrives,
我希望你能更负责任一点
I want you to work on being a little more responsible.
懂了吗?
Comprende?
懂了
Comprende.
击掌
High five on it.
漂亮! 啊哈甜甜圈主人和蓝蓝侠又回来了!
Yeah! Donut lord and the blue blur are back at it again!
抓紧了
Hang on.
快艇来咯
Speedboat!
索尼克
Sonic!
一起去夏威夷, 你有多开心?
How excited are you, going to Hawaii with me?
哦耶
Oh, yeah!
欢迎来到索尼克航空, 最快的旅行方式
Welcome to Sonic air, the fastest way to travel.
现在第一组和第二组进入
Now boarding groups one and two.
索尼克 这太有趣了
Sonic, this is so fun!
不好意思, 这位女士, 您是第三组, 请等一下才会轮到你
I'm sorry, ma'am, you're group three. Please wait your turn.
- 第一组和第二组有人吗? 没人? -让它别沉浸其中了
- Anyone from groups one and two? Nobody? - Just let him get it out of his system.
好的, 那么其他人都往这边走
Okay, then everybody else right this way.
谢谢
Thank you.
到你了, 先生
And you, sir?
检测到一件糟糕的衬衫
Terrible shirt detected.
我们走了哦
There we go.
好了, 你可以走了, 祝你旅途愉快, 再见
Okay, you're free to go. Enjoy your trip. Bye-bye now.
好吧
Okay.
要来抱抱吗
Bring it in.
汤姆, 我第一次一个人当家
Tom, I'm about to be hedgehog of the house for the first time.
我觉得我需要成熟一点了, 用抱抱告别不合适
I think I'm a little mature to hug you goodbye.
好吧, 那要不碰个拳?
Okay, what about a power bump?
-碰拳? -对, 碰拳!
- Power bump? - Yes, power bump.
就是这样
That's more like it.
-瓦乔夫斯基! -瓦乔夫斯基!
- Wachowski! - Wachowski!
好的, 用这个回家
Okay, use this one to get back home.
好了 我们走了 乖点
All right, we're off. Be good.
对了, 你有我们的电话号码哦
Yes. You have our number.
很抱歉听不见!
Sorry! Can't hear you!
你正在穿越一个跨维度的地方!
You're traveling through a cross-dimensional portal!
- 已经开始想你了! -好吧?
- Miss you already! - Okay?
在瑞秋的婚礼上玩得开心!
Have fun at Rachel's wedding!
他们回来还有48小时
Okay, it's 48 hours until they come back.
我们有电视TV, 上网, 一屋子吃的, 没有人监视
We've got TV channels, streaming channels, a house full of food and no supervision.
我们尽情嗨吧
Let's do this.
如果这些读数准确, 他应该就在这里
If these readings are accurate, he's here.
我找到他了!
I found him!
希望我不会太晚
I just hope I'm not too late.
很接近了
He's close.
我只需要找到一个不被发现的方法
I just need a way to reach him without being spotted.
标准的人力交通工具, 完美
Standard human transport. Perfect.
哦, 天啊
Oh, boy.
嗨
Aloha!
-怎么样, 伙计  - 你知道的
- How's it going, bud? - Oh, you know.
依然安静的夜晚, 在家看着书呗
Just a quiet night at home, settling in with a good book.
- 你呢? 你怎么了? -我打电话只是想说我们到了这个地方
- And you? What's up with you? - I was just calling to say we're here.
但现在你说的每一句话都让我怀疑
But now every word out of your mouth is making me suspicious.
什么啊?
What?
你得放松点, 伙计 你应该在瓦胡岛四季酒店
You got to relax, buddy. You're at the four seasons oahu.
来一杯鸡尾酒, 享受和你妻子在一起的时光
Have a Mai Tai. Enjoy some time with your wife.
然后在某个地方做些羞羞的事情
Get sunburned somewhere embarrassing.
这个周末是你的
This weekend is about you.
你知道吗? 你说得对 我记得我们碰过拳的
You know what? You're right. We power-bumped on it.
所以不管你在做什么
So whatever it is you're doing,
我相信你能在我们回家的时复原一切, 对吗?
I'm sure you can undo it by the time we get home, yeah?
当然, 我的意思是, 被这样怀疑让我感到有种被冒犯的感觉不是吗
Exactly! I mean, I am deeply offended by such accusations!
瑞秋的未婚对象如何呀?
So, how's Rachel's fiance?
他本人和照片上一样好看吗?
Is he as good-looking in person as he is in pictures?
好像看起来还行
Somehow better-looking.
哇! 看来你就要成为家里第三位帅哥了
Wow! You're about to be the third best-looking dude in the family.
而且, 嘿, 还是在婚礼殿台上
But, hey, still on the podium.
好吧, 我去自我介绍一下
All right, I better go and introduce myself.
别惹麻烦
Stay out of trouble.
麻烦? 闹哪样, 这里的一切就都很正常啊
Trouble? Don't worry. Everything here is completely normal.
嗯哼, 晚安, 伙计
Uh-huh. Night, bud.
嘿! 我过来打个招呼
Hey! I was just coming over to say hi.
你对我未婚妻所做的事, 你还有勇气来这里
You've got a lot of nerve coming up in here after what you did to my fiancee.
- 等等, 什么? -比如她的车?
- Wait. What? - Totaling her car?
再比如把她绑在椅子上? 我想我应该把你大卸八块
Leaving her tied to a chair? I should rip you limb from limb.
天哪, 看看你的脸!
Oh, my god, look at your face!
汤姆, 冷静, 宝贝, 我开玩笑的
Tommy, breathe, baby. Breathe. I was kidding.
-嘿, 伙计, 我真的在开玩笑  -好吧
- Hey, man, I was totally kidding. - Okay.
-你在开玩笑 -是啊
- You were kidding. - Yeah.
抱歉啦, 瑞秋让我这么做的, 这完全是她的主意
I'm sorry. Rachel put me up to it. It was totally her idea.
真流氓
That rascal.
听着, 我不知道你是否知道. 瑞秋根本不在乎你
Listen, I don't know if you're aware. Rachel does not care for you at all.
我知道 是啊
I'm aware. Yeah.
说真的, 兄弟, 你还有工作要做
Seriously, bro, you got work to do.
-嘿!  -嘿!
- Hey! - Hey.
很高兴见到你! 谢谢你来, 汤姆
Good to see you! Thanks for coming, Tom.
-真高兴你来了 -真的?
- Really glad you came. - Really?
我也很高兴见到你 祝贺
Great to see you, too. Congratulations.
我的意思是, 你们在一起会很幸福
I mean, you guys, you guys seem really happy together.
你知道的, 你说得对, 托马斯·沃乔夫斯基
You know, you're all right, Thomas wachowski.
-我们能和好吗? -我很乐意
- Can we Bury the hatchet? - I'd love that.
-是吗? -是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
-好了, 抱一下了啦 -太棒了
- All right, bring it in! - All right! Great.
如果你搞砸了我的婚礼, 我会毙了你
And if you screw up my wedding, I will end you.
好了奥兹, 这是索尼克之家的电影之夜
All right, ozzy, it's movie night at casa de Sonic,
轮到你选频道了
And it's your turn to pick.
但我不会再看雪狗了
But I am not watching snow dogs again.
那部电影太差劲了!
That movie is the worst!
停电了!
Blackout!
奥兹
Ozzy.
抱歉, 伙计 没事的
Sorry, buddy. Everything's okay.
我们可不玩恶作剧啊
Excuse me. We did not order a poltergeist.
如果门外是送披萨那个家伙, 那这真的不太专业呢
If this is the pizza guy, this is really unprofessional.
蛋人?
Eggman?
好久不见, 小刺猬
Hello, hedgehog.
你想我没?
Did you miss me?
我不知道你是怎么回来的, 但你来这里是大错特错
I don't know how you got back, but you made a big mistake coming here.
恰恰相反, 伙计
Au contraire, mon frere.
上次PK你以为你完胜
The mistake was thinking you'd won.
但那只是一个插曲, 一个开胃小菜而已
But that was just a prelude, an hors d'oeuvre,
一杯开胃酒
An aperitif, an amuse-bouche.
我懂了
I get it.
我想你不会懂的
I don't think you do.
不过马上你就懂了
But you're about to.
顺带加上那个白痴警长和他的妻子
And so will that idiot sheriff and his wife.
最后还有你的小狗一起
And your little dog too!
真可怜
Pitiful.
什么? 你是谁?
What? Who are you?
我是不是很没礼貌?
Where are my manners?
索尼克, 介绍下这是纳克尔斯
Sonic, meet knuckles.
我的新朋友
My new bffae.
永远的好朋友!
Bestest friend forever and ever!
听着机器蛋人, 我不管你带谁来帮你
Look, robotnik, I don't care who you brought to help you.
你永远得不到我的力量
You're never going to get my power.
那我看起来像是需要你的力量吗?
Do I look like I need your power?
如果恶魔真的存在的话, 那真是太好了
So nice when diabolical evil lives up to the hype.
它在哪里?
Where is it?
你想要吗? 那来了
You want it? Here it comes.
我还以为你会更厉害呢, 你根本没招
I was expecting more of you. You're unskilled.
没有受过训练
Untrained.
你不配!
And unworthy!
你忘了我还有一招叫"势不可挡".
You forgot one. Unstoppable.
我注定要做我祖先做不到的事
It is my destiny to do what my ancestors could not...
恢复我族人家园的终极力量
To restore the ultimate power to the home of my people.
终极力量? 我不知道你在说什么
Ultimate power? I don't know what you're talking about.
你找错人了
You've got the wrong guy.
终极力量?
Ultimate power?
现在你说的是我口头禅.
Now you're speaking my language.
别跟我装傻, 长爪的徒弟
Don't play dumb with me, apprentice of longclaw.
你认识长爪?
You knew longclaw?
长爪和她的族人是我们部落的宿敌
Longclaw and her people were the sworn enemy of my tribe, the echidna.
我们在他们手中战斗和牺牲, 现在你将在我的手中死去
We fought and died at their hands, and now you will die at mine.
快点, 上车, 我是站在你这边的
Come on. Get in! I'm on your side.
抱歉, 你是哪位?
I'm sorry. Who are you?
好吧, 不重要了
You know what? It doesn't matter.
带我离开这里! 快, 快, 快, 快!
Get us out of here! Go, go, go, go, go!
他是个癫了!
He's gone rabid!
真恶心, 他在舔吗?
Gross! Is he licking it?
再见!
See ya!
劝你打针吃点药, 蛋人!
Make sure to get your shots, eggman!
哇哦, 很荣幸终于见到你了, 索尼克
Wow. Okay. Let me just say it is an honor to finally meet you, Sonic.
我可以叫你索尼克吗?
Is it okay if I call you Sonic?
大家都叫我尾巴, 你想知道为什么吗?
Everyone calls me tails. You're probably wondering why.
让我猜猜, 是因为多了个尾巴吗?
Let me guess. Because of the extra tail?
没错, 我就知道你会明白的
That's right! I should've known you'd get that.
酷, 对了, 这是怎么回事? 机器蛋人怎么回来?
Cool. Also, what is going on? Robotnik's back?
谁是克利福德, 那个愤怒的红色大怪物?
And who is Clifford the big red rage monster?
那是纳克尔斯,最后一批针鼹
That's knuckles, the last of the echidnas...
也是银河系最危险的战士
And the most dangerous warrior in the galaxy.
他一心想找到翡翠大师
He's obsessed with finding the master emerald.
你是认真的吗? 翡翠大师?
Are you serious? The master emerald?
那只是个睡前故事
That's just a bedtime story.
但他相信这是真的
Well, he believes it's real.
他一直认为你是找到翡翠大师的关键
And he must think you're the key to finding it.
红灯! 把方向盘给我!
Red light! Give me the wheel!
- 嘿你干嘛…-把脚挪开
- Hey, what are you... - Move your foot.
我想我们甩掉他了
I think we lost him.
看来没有甩掉他, 我们真的没有甩掉他!
We did not lose him. We definitely did not lose him!
我有个主意, 你信我吗?
I've got an idea. Do you trust me?
当然不信, 我才刚认识你!
Of course not! I literally just met you!
- 还是让我来吧 -你在干什么?
- Just let me. Come on! - What are you doing?
我们在飞
We're flying.
你的屁股变成直升机了吗?
Did your butt just turn into a helicopter?
屁股直升机!
A butt-copter!
只有你索尼克才能想出这叫法
Only Sonic the hedgehog could come up with something like that.
狡猾的招数
Foxy move.
如果你想把事情做好…
You want something done right...
你必须雇一个你可以随意摆布的人
You have to hire someone you can push around.
全部大写
All caps.
博士, 你在那里?
Doctor, where are you?
怪胎
Freak.
(博士的消息: 准备好我的拿铁咖啡)
我, 我很抱歉, 各位
I, I'm sorry, folks.
我得早点关门, 大家都出去!
I have to close early. Everybody out!
大家都出去, 谢谢你们来我店里喝咖啡
Everybody out. Thank you for visiting the mean bean.
好的, 晚安, 晚安
All right, good night. Good night.
他回来了
He's back.
He's back!
这才像话
That's more like it.
我又重生了!
I've been re-hatched!
所以, 那位拥有巨大超能力的朋友,
So, my massively metacarpaled friend,
你提到…
You mentioned...
终极力量
Ultimate power.
是在类似房子那种建筑里吗?
Back at the house?
你是说翡翠大师?
The master emerald?
这不关你的事
It does not concern you.
我把你从那个星球救出来, 然后你把我带到刺猬这里
I got you off that planet and you brought me to the hedgehog.
我们已经没有合作价值了
We have no more use for each other.
好吧我不想跟你唱反调, 不过…
Well, I hate to be a contrarian, but...
我想我们还可以继续合作
I think we might.
你觉得这些机器能和我对抗?
You think these machines are a match for me?
我能把它们撕得粉碎
I will shatter them like the bones from a fallen...
原来是梯子
They are stairs.
你看, 地球是我的地盘
You see, earth is my turf, g.
如果你不知道开源高科技程序, 没有我你会迷路的
If you don't know how to floss, you'll be lost without me.
你刚说的什么我简直听不懂
I understand nothing of what you just said.
我能帮你找到翡翠大师, 然后你用它来. .
I help you retrieve the emerald, and you use it to...
消灭王八蛋刺猬!
Destroy the hedgehog!
你的意思是你我结盟
You're suggesting an alliance.
在地球, 我们一般用握手的方式表示达成协议
Around here we simply grip each other's hands tightly.
你这个野蛮的太空乡巴佬!
You truculent space bumpkin!
你把我可爱的小手弄伤了!
You've crushed my favorite hand!
真的吗? 我的手一点感觉都没有
Really? My hand is uninjured.
但我赞同你的想法
But I'm now convinced of your commitment.
"哦, 太好了"
"Oh, goody,"
他同意了, 到最后再同时重置纳克尔斯他们两个刺猬
He exclaimed, while he reset two of his knuckles.
我. .
I'm...
很高兴能加入这个团队
Delighted to be on the same team.
公路旅行!
Road trip!
你坐靠窗位置
I'll let you stick your nose out the window.
索尼克, 我们在哪?
Sonic, where are we?
欢迎来到韦德基地
Welcome to the Wade cave.
我希望有一天能对一个女人说这句话
Which is something I hope to someday say to a woman.
一个不是我妈妈的女人
A woman who's not my mom.
韦德 认真点
Wade, focus.
我们得搞清楚为什么纳克尔斯认为我是找到翡翠大师的关键
We need to figure out why knuckles thinks I'm the key to finding the master emerald.
他为什么提到长爪?
And why did he mention longclaw?
这其中一定有关联
There must be a connection.
等等, 有了
Wait a minute. There is.
看, 长爪鸟给我的地图上有个翡翠宝石符号
Look. There's an emerald symbol on the map longclaw gave me.
我以前从来不知道这是什么意思
I never knew what it meant before.
有什么东西亮了
Something's happening.
长爪?
Longclaw?
你好, 索尼克
Hello, Sonic.
如果你正在看这个, 说明我出事了
If you're watching this, then something has happened to me.
我祈祷你能平安到达地球
And I pray you've made it to earth unharmed.
地球之所以被选中, 有一个非常重要的原因
This world has been chosen for a very important reason.
那是翡翠宝石的秘密藏身处
It's the secret location of the master emerald.
翡翠宝石拥有将思想变为现实的力量
The emerald has the power to turn thoughts into reality.
就像《捉鬼敢死队》里的绵花糖鬼
Like the stay puft marshmallow man from ghostbusters.
如果落入坏人之手, 可能会威胁到宇宙中的所有生命
In the wrong hands it could threaten all life in the universe.
保护翡翠是我神圣的职责
Protecting the emerald was my sacred duty.
现在我必须把这个责任交给你
And now I must pass that responsibility to you.
这将是属于我的责任
This is my moment.
跟着地图, 找到翡翠, 保护它
Follow the map, find the emerald, and keep it safe.
亲爱的索尼克
My dear Sonic,
你有一颗我从未见过的心
You have a heart like no creature I've ever known.
我好爱你
I love you so much.
再见了
Goodbye.
不, 不, 不, 等等
No, no, no, wait.
我不会让你失望的, 长爪鸟
I won't let you down, longclaw.
那是你爸爸吗?
So is that you, your dad?
什么?
What?
不对吗?
No?
根据这张地图, 第一条线索在西伯利亚
According to this map, the first clue is in Siberia.
这是一个能指引我们找到翡翠的指南针
It's a compass that will lead to the emerald.
而且纳克尔斯已经在这里了, 这是一场比赛
And with knuckles already here, it's a race.
纳克尔斯
Knuckles?
我在中学认识一个叫纳克尔斯的孩子
I knew a kid in middle school named knuckles.
他可以把整个拳头塞进嘴里
Could fit his whole fist in his mouth.
如果是同一个纳克尔斯, 我们就完蛋了
If this is the same knuckles, we are screwed.
这个纳克尔斯, 那个纳克尔斯, 都不影响
This knuckles, that knuckles. It doesn't matter.
我们要先到那个地方去
We're gonna get there first.
"我们"是什么意思?
What do you mean,"we"?
你跟我一起
You're coming with me.
不, 不, 不
No, no, no, no, no.
我想告诉你, 我不擅长野外行动
I just came here to warn you. I'm not a field guy.
别担心, 我会保护你的, 我不会让你出事的
Don't worry. I got your back. I won't let anything happen to you.
这是"碰拳", 在地球上, 这意味着一个无法打破的承诺
It's a power bump. On earth, it means an unbreakable promise.
好吧, 我加入
Okay, I'm in.
博士, 真的是你
Doctor. It's really you.
你看起来不一样了
You look different.
你爸爸又有了新长的胡子
Papa's got a brand new 'stache.
我就知道, 我就知道! 我就知道你会回来的, 先生
I knew it. I knew it! I knew you'd come back, sir.
我一直在做你爱喝的拿铁山羊奶
I never stopped steaming your Austrian goat's milk.
来点蘑菇吧
Could use some mushroom.
你带来了谁
You brought something.
像是某种太空豪猪
Some kind of space porcupine.
太空豪猪, 我是针鼹鼠!
Porcupine? I am an echidna!
从出生就接受各种形式的致命战斗训练,
Trained since birth in all forms of lethal combat,
注定要恢复我部落的荣誉,
Destined to restore honor to my tribe,
并且愿意摧毁任何挡我道的东西
And willing to destroy anything that gets in my way.
欢迎加入我们
Welcome to the team.
这说明他信任你,"石头"
That means he trusts you, stone.
现在让我们重新变换下这个地方!
Now let's renovate this dump!
(语音启动命令):"拿铁奥地利山羊奶"
Latte with steamed Austrian goat milk!
好球相当不错
Good one. Solid.
-抱歉伙计们 -这就是比赛!
- Sorry, fellas. - That's game!
我们干得漂亮! 干得漂亮!
That's how we do! That's how we do!
-毕竟是他们擅长的嘛? -团队合作使得梦想成真!
- But are they good at math? - Teamwork makes the dream work!
很抱歉, 大个子汤姆
Sorry about that, big Tom.
-你没事吧? -没事没事
- Are you good? - All good. Fine.
嘿, 谢谢你邀请我和你的伴郎们一起玩
Hey. Thanks for inviting me out to hang with you and your groomsmen.
高质量的配合
Good quality bonding.
你知道吗, 兄弟
You know, bro,
那边的那些人, 他们可比我的伴郎厉害多了
Those guys right there, they're way more than my groomsmen.
这是我的战友
That's my squad.
没有他们, 我这辈子都活不下去
Never would've made it through life without 'em.
过来啊!
Get over here!
我来了, 我来了!
Yeah, I'm coming! I'm coming!
-回头见 -好的!
- I'll catch you later. - Hey. Yeah!
如果你准备好做力量瑜伽了就告诉我
Let me know if you're ready for some power yoga.
-当然 -来吧小汤姆加油
- You bet. - Come on, Tommy boy. Let's go.
加油
Let's go.
别逼我
Don't make me.
我在干什么?
What am I doing?
嘿汤姆叔叔!
Hey, uncle Tommy!
嘿, 姑娘们!
Hey, girls!
你好
How you do.
-那些是结婚戒指吗? -是的
- Are those the wedding rings? - Uh-huh.
可以看看吗?
May I?
她对待小魔戒的工作非常认真哦!
This little ring bearer has been taking her job very seriously.
-她整个早上都在练习 -我看出来了
- She's been practicing all morning. - I can see that.
你真有责任心
How very responsible of you.
不过不是应该有两个结婚戒指吗?
Except aren't there supposed to be two wedding rings?
啊哦
Uh-oh.
-汤姆叔叔? -等等这是怎么回事?
- Uncle Tommy? - Hang on. What's going on here?
你会做得很好的, 孩子
You're gonna do great, kiddo.
拜
Bye.
-嘿宝贝 -嗨
- Hey, baby. - Hi.
没错! 新郎在楼里!
That's right! Groom in the building!
看看那些家伙
Look at those guys.
我希望索尼克也能这样
I wish Sonic had that.
-肌肉男? -控制一下自己
- Muscles? - Control yourself.
不, 伙伴, 僚人, 一个小队
No. Buddies. Wingmen. A squad.
索尼克没有这种东西, 他是单飞
Sonic doesn't have anything like that. He's flying solo.
宝贝, 你别这么想
Baby, you got to relax.
你在四季酒店
You're at the four seasons.
喝杯鸡尾酒, 陪陪你老婆
Have a Mai Tai. Spend some time with your wife.
他就是这么说的, 说真的, 他的原话
That's what he said. Seriously, his exact words.
看到了吗? 他是个聪明的孩子  他会找到路的
See? He's a smart kid. He'll find his way.
我完全找不到路
I absolutely cannot find my way.
我们彻底彻底地, 彻底地, 彻底地迷路了
We are completely, totally, unequivocally lost.
索尼克, 在这种天气
Sonic, in this weather,
这东西不可能有读数的!
There's no way we're gonna get any readings on this thing!
-我们要回去吗? -不不不
- Should we go back? - No, no, no.
前面有灯光, 也许我们可以在那里避避
There's a light up ahead. Maybe we can take shelter in there.
完美
Perfect.
你确定吗? 我们不知道里面是谁
Are you sure about this? We don't know who's inside.
别担心, 在地球上, 人们非常热情好客
Don't worry. On earth, people are very welcoming,
喜欢带陌生人回家
And love taking complete strangers into their homes.
跑吧
Run.
请给我两个人的桌子!
Table for two, please!
你要点什么?
What would you like to order?
请来两份炖牛肉
Two beef stews, please.
-你从哪儿弄来这么酷的小玩意? -我发明的
- Where'd you get all these cool gadgets? - I invented 'em.
这是我的专长
That's kinda my thing.
事实上, 是我的发明让我发现了你
In fact, my inventions are how I discovered you.
还记得那晚在棒球场吗?
Remember that night at the baseball field?
你的能量冲击波一路到达了我的母星
Your energy blast reached all the way to my home planet.
我看到你从那个胡子男手里救了全村的人
I saw you save your whole village from that crazy mustache guy.
等等, 所以你一直在监视我?
Wait, so you've been watching me this whole time?
即使是在洗澡的时候?
Even in the shower?
这是一个棘手的问题
That's a trick question.
刺猬索尼克更喜欢泡泡浴
Sonic the hedgehog prefers bubble baths.
伙计, 你真厉害!
Man, you're good!
当我知道纳克尔斯在追踪你的时候,
When I learned knuckles was on your trail,
我知道我不能再袖手旁观了
I knew I couldn't just sit back and watch anymore.
我必须来告诉你
I had to come warn you.
什么? 等一下
What? Hang on one sec.
甜甜圈主人来了
Donut lord is checking in.
"放松一下, 看看电视"
"Just chilling. Watching TV. "
点, 点, 点
Dot, dot, dot.
博士
Doctor,
我们为什么要和这个白痴合作?
Why are we working with this imbecile?
因为那个头脑简单的太空豪猪是开启奇迹的关键
Because that simpleminded space trash is the key to something extraordinary.
帮你向刺猬复仇的东西
Something to help you get revenge on the hedgehog.
想大一点, 斯通
Think bigger, stone.
他寻找的翡翠宝石对我疯狂的设计有很大帮助
The emerald he seeks could power my wildest designs.
我卓越的才能不会仅限于地球
My genius wouldn't just be recognized on earth.
它会像病毒一样传播到银河系的每个角落
It would spread virally to every corner of the galaxy,
让我能够驾驭宇宙中所有的负面力量
Allowing me to harness all the negative forces of the universe...
与黑暗本身交流
And commune with darkness itself.
哇, 听起来很大
Wow. That sounds big.
这是写在我愿望板上多年来的梦想  这就是吸引力法则
It's been on my vision board for years. It's the law of attraction.
你没看到秘密吗?
Didn't you see the secret?
卡普洛伊
Kaplooey!
Kaplooey.
又一个在家无聊的夜晚  "
"Another boring night at home. "
刺猬回家了!
The hedgehog has returned home!
Falsa  在拉丁语里是"错了"的意思
Falsa. Which is Latin for "wrong-o. "
根据我的全球网络基站三角测量结果他在撒谎,
According to my worldwide network cell tower triangulation, he's lying,
一直都在撒谎
All the way...
来自西伯利亚东部雄伟的腹地
From the majestic hinterlands of eastern Siberia.
他是个异地恋骗子!
He's a long-distance liar!
是啊, 还有更多呢
Yeah, there's more where that came from.
魔法小刺猬被摧毁
Tiny magic hedgehog destroyed.
现在让我们开始探索吧
Now let's begin our quest.
等待
Wait.
你的仆人呢? 山羊挤奶工
What about your Minion? The goat milker.
船上没有斯通的位置
There's no room on the ship for stone.
要我说, 甩掉他, 甩掉他
I say we ditch him, ghost him, blow him off.
耻辱!
Dishonor!
"这"就是我的风格
"Dis" is how I roll.
对不起, 我点的是炖牛肉
I'm sorry, but I asked for the beef stew.
你的口气闻起来像山羊粪便
Your breath smells like goat poop.
你说什么?
What did you say?
大家过来看
Come and take a look.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
也许他们以为今天是我的生日?
Maybe they think it's my birthday?
别担心, 我会处理的  好了, 各位, 放松点
Don't worry, I'll take care of this. Okay, everybody, take it easy.
我相信一定有很好的解决方式
I'm sure there's a perfectly good explanation...
不管我朋友说了什么, 做了什么
For whatever my friend said or did.
退后
Stand back.
我刚放屁了
I just farted.
喵喵?
Meow?
把这些怪物扔进火里!
Throw these monsters in the fire!
哦, 不, 不, 别这样, 伙计们, 放松点, 我们好好谈谈
Oh, no, no. Come on, guys. Take it easy. Let's talk this through.
我们好好谈谈!
Let's talk this through!
别别别, 扫描西伯利亚
Come on, come on. Scanning siberian customs.
- 这机器一定有什么故障 -尾巴, 你在干什么, 快点啊
- There's got to be something in here. - Tails, whatever you're doing, do it fast.
我想我找到了!
I think I got it!
Pivonka Pivonka
Pivonka! Pivonka!
Pivonka
Pivonka!
好
Da.
Pivonka
Pivonka!
尾巴, 什么是"pivonka"?
Tails, what's a "pivonka"?
好像是西伯利亚人解决问题的惯用方式
It's a siberian custom to resolve disputes.
如果我们赢了, 他们就放我们走  如果我们输了…
If we win, they let us go. If we lose...
好了, 我们得拿上地图离开这里
Okay, we have to grab the map and get out of here.
地图在哪里?
Where's the map?
哦, 不  我把它落在桌子上了! 看!
Oh, no. I left it on the table! Look!
什么鬼
What?
天啊, 这是舞蹈比赛
Oh, my god, it's a dance fight.
索尼克, 我们该怎么办?
Sonic, what do we do?
我们只能跳舞, 然后拿到地图
We dance and get that map.
开始了
Here we go.
好了, 现在开始  不, 我们要去…
Okay, now let's do. No, we're gonna go...
好吧
Okay.
地图! 快来, 我们抓住它!
The map! Come on, let's grab it!
你想要这个?
You want?
过来拿
Come get.
怪胎!
Freaks!
怪胎! 怪胎! 怪胎!
Freaks! Freaks! Freaks!
怎么了, 尾巴? 振作点, 我需要你!
What's wrong, tails? Come on. I need you!
我做不到, 索尼克  我不像你那么勇敢
I can't do this, Sonic. I'm not brave like you.
我的小玩意把我们搞得一团糟, 我还弄丢了你的地图,
My gadget got us in this mess, and I lost your map,
我们会被扔进火堆里的!
And we're gonna get tossed into a fire!
新的DJ来了
New DJ coming in.
来吧, 伙计, 看我的
Come on, pal. I got an idea.
他们叫我们怪胎,
They called us freaks,
所以让我们变得怪异
So let's get freaky.
跟着我的脚步放心好了
Just follow my moves. You'll be fine.
漂亮! 还有伴舞!
All right! Backup dancers!
走起来!
Here we go!
这上面有很多我的影子!
There's a lot of me up here!
我爱pivonka!
I love pivonka!
大下马! (体操动作)
And big dismount!
耶!
Yeah!
我拿到了
I'll take that.
我们成功了!
We did it!
太神奇了, 干得好, 尾巴
That was amazing! Way to go, tails.
只有刺猬索尼克才能赢得史诗般的舞蹈比赛
Wow. Only Sonic the hedgehog could win a dance battle that epic.
所以跟着我, 伙计
Well, stick with me, pal.
地球可能是一个陌生可怕的地方, 但我知道这个蓝色古老星球的每一件事
Earth can be a scary place, but I know everything about this old pale blue dot.
真的吗?
Do you really mean that?
也不是不是所有事情  但我看了很多电视频道…
I mean, not everything. But I watch a lot of discovery channel and...
我想说我是你的朋友吗?
I meant about me being your pal.
当然, 朋友
Of course, buddy.
这么热情
Comin' in hot.
从小到大, 我一个朋友都没有
Growing up, I didn't have any friends.
我们村的人都觉得我的两条尾巴很奇怪
Everyone in my village thought my two tails were weird.
嘿, 我知道那种感觉
Hey, I know that feeling.
然后我看到了你, 银河系最快的生物
But then I saw you, the fastest creature in the galaxy.
你也很奇怪  但你是一个传奇
You were weird too. But you were a legend.
这让我想, 也许古怪也没那么糟
That made me think, maybe being weird isn't so bad.
你激励我离开我的村庄
You inspired me to leave my village,
找到你, 帮助你完成任务
To find you and help you in your mission.
我真的很高兴你来了, 尾巴
I'm really glad you're here, tails.
我也很开心我能在这里和索尼克一起
I'm glad I'm here too, Sonic.
好吧, 还是睡一会儿吧
Well, might as well get some sleep.
感觉这是个过夜的好地方
This feels like a good place to spend the night.
你的小发明上会有清晰的读数
You'll be able to get clear readings on your gizmo thing.
晚安, 尾巴
Night, tails.
尾巴, 尾巴, 出状况了
Tails. Tails. We have a situation.
天气预报, 今天的天气晴朗
Today's forecast calls for clear, sunny skies.
我定位了精确坐标, 就在前面
I pinpointed the coordinates. It's right up ahead.
嘿, 尾巴, 等等我
Hey, tails. Wait up.
好吧, 我们发现了一个巨大的猫头鹰门, 看起来很宏大
Okay, we got a giant owl door. Seems encouraging.
看看这个
Check this out.
-你能翻译一下吗? -没问题
- Can you translate that? - Yeah.
很久以前, 一群可怕的战士
Ages ago, a fearsome group of warriors,
被称为针鼹
Known as the echidnas,
铸造了七颗宝石
Forged the seven chaos emeralds.
翡翠大师
The master emerald.
有了它, 一个战士
With it, a single warrior.
没有人相信会拥有这样的力量
Believing no one should have such power,
一群英雄找到了绿宝石
An order of heroes recovered the emerald.
听起来像是猫头鹰和针鼹
Sounds like the owls and the echidnas.
就像范·迪塞尔和摇滚乐队
Like vin diesel and the rock.
等等我
Wait for me.
巨大的猫头鹰门, 和巨大的猫头鹰  令人深刻
Okay, giant owl door, giant owl. Makes sense.
等一下  我以前见过这些符号
Wait a second. I've seen these symbols before.
要来了哦
Here we go.
嗯, 这起作用了
Well, that did something.
-指南针! -这会带我们找到翡翠!
- The compass! - This will lead us to the emerald!
嘿, 你身上有点东西. .
Hey, you got a little something on your...
哦, 不, 尾巴, 退后
Oh, no. Tails, get back.
快跑
Run!
又是那家伙?
That guy again?
小心了, 我的小石笋, 是有人叫了优步吗
Heads up, my little stalagmites. Someone call an uber?
嘿, 谢谢你帮我做了这么多难事
Hey, thanks for doing all the hard stuff.
接下来由我们接手
But we'll take it from here.
好吧, 我们得谈谈你的新造型
Okay, we really gotta talk about your new look.
就像 x 教授遇到了大富翁
It's like professor x meets the monopoly man.
什么样的天才会开敞篷车去西伯利亚?
And what kind of genius shows up to Siberia in a convertible?
像我们这种天才都是热情高涨的…
The kind of genius that can turn up the heat...
只需轻轻按一下开关
With a flick of a switch.
好一个! 我想那应该没事
Good one! I'm sure that wasn't important.
尾巴, 那是出口, 我们走
Tails, that's our exit. Come on.
我们分头行动
Let's split up.
-你上我下 -好的
- You go high, I go low. - Right.
快速伸展一下, 来咯
Quick little stretch and here we go.
想跟我玩吗?
So you want to play?
这招不错
That's new.
索尼克
Sonic!
打雪仗!
Snowball fight!
太简单了, 来吧, 挑战我!
It's too easy. Come on, challenge me!
我们在乎的是造型加潇洒
We are talking style and pizzazz.
漂亮! 我这波操作太牛了
Yeah! I make this look good.
哦, 真好, 冬兵
Oh, great. The winter soldier.
对于一个叫纳克尔斯的人来说, 你真的不擅长打架
For a guy named knuckles, you are really bad at punching.
交出罗盘! 你不是我的对手
Surrender the compass! You are no match for me.
我这辈子都在为此训练
I've been training for this my entire life.
我没有受过任何训练, 但是现在我在你前面呀
And I had no training at all, yet here I am ahead of you.
是不是很尴尬
That's gotta be embarrassing.
我的戒指!
My rings!
有人告诉过你, 你有严重的情绪问题吗?
Has anyone ever told you you've got serious anger issues?
你用无聊的笑话嘲笑我,
You mock me with your weak jokes,
你对我一无所知, 刺猬
But you know nothing about me, hedgehog.
我知道你们这些针鼹总是不请自来, 还毁了我的生活
Well, I know you echidnas have a habit of showing up uninvited and ruining my life.
毁了你的生活? 开什么玩笑
Ruining your life? Another bad joke.
因为你我是真的失去了一切
I lost everything because of you.
我的部落即将取得最大的胜利
My tribe was on the verge of its greatest victory.
最后一个猫头鹰战士被找到了
The last of the owl warriors had been located.
长爪的翡翠秘密即将属于我们部落的时候
Soon longclaw's emerald secrets would be ours.
但我父亲阻止我加入战斗
But my father stopped me from joining the fight.
他说我继承家族荣誉的那一刻迟早会到来
He said my moment to honor our tribe would come,
但不是现在
But it was not this moment.
这是他对我说的最后一句话
Those were the last words he spoke to me.
之后我再也没见过他
I never saw him again.
那天我们都失去了一切
We both lost everything that day.
- 再见, 索尼克 -不!
- Goodbye, Sonic. - No!
长爪!
Longclaw!
索尼克, 你没事吧?
Sonic! Are you okay?
骗子!
Deceiver!
不, 我没有骗你
No, it wasn't a trick.
尾巴, 拿着罗盘先离开这里
Tails, take the compass and get out of here!
耶
Yeah!
回见, 讨厌鬼们!
Later, haters!
尾巴
Tails!
尾巴, 快醒醒啊!
Tails, come on. Wake up.
他选择帮助狐狸而不是追求指南针
He chose helping the fox over pursuing the compass.
当然了, 新朋友, 同样可悲的弱点
Of course he did. New friend, same pathetic weakness.
哦, 不, 不, 不, 不, 我们真的有麻烦了
Oh, no. No, no, no. We're in real trouble here.
快点, 尾巴, 我需要你带我们飞离这里
Come on, tails. I need you to fly us out of here.
该起床了
Time to wake up.
再见, 孩子们, 好好享受新鲜的奶粉吧
See ya, kids. Enjoy the fresh powder.
你有没有. .
Did you...
这些戒指代表. .
These rings signify the...
抱歉
Sorry.
我以为它是静音的
Thought it was on silent.
这些戒指. .
These rings...
求求你了, 汤姆思!
So help me, Thomas!
抱歉实在抱歉
Okay, sorry, sorry.
对不起, 这是紧急情况
Excuse me, this is an emergency.
抱歉
Sorry.
什么? 最好是重要的事, 我只是. .
What? This better be important. I just...
你在滑雪吗?
Are you skiing?
是在滑雪, 但我现在急需你的帮助
Snowboarding, actually. But I need your help now.
生死攸关
Life or death situation this very second.
我需要你用我给你的戒指来救我
I need you to use the ring I gave you to save me.
就现在
Like right now.
好吧, 慢点说, 我都不知道你在哪
Okay, slow down. I don't even know where you are.
你只需要想象一下, 你想让戒指指指向哪里
You just gotta picture where you want the ring to go.
快想象一下
So picture this.
哦, 天哪, 好的, 好的, 等等
Oh, my god. Okay, okay. Hang on.
不会吧?
What?
是你扔的吗?
Did you throw it?
-哦 天哪 -什么? 告诉我"哦天哪"是什么
- Oh, god. - What? Tell me what "oh, god. "
我逗乔乔的时候把戒指弄混了
I mixed up the rings when I was teasing jojo.
什么? 那它在哪儿? 那它在哪儿?
What? Where is it then? Where is it then?
你不会想知道的
You don't want to know.
我想知道, 汤姆
But I do, Tom.
我很想知道
I very much want to know,
在我变成刺猬口味的雪糕之前
Before I become a hedgehog-flavored snow cone.
坚持住, 伙计, 我来处理
Hang tight, buddy. I got this.
有了这个戒指, 瑞秋
With this ring, Rachel...
嘿! 嗨
Hey! Hi.
没事吧, 伙计?
Everything okay, bud?
-没有 -你在干什么?
- Not really. - What are you doing?
这听起来可能有点疯狂, 但我需要看一下那个戒指, 就一秒钟
This is gonna sound crazy, but I need to see that ring for just one second, one second.
- 你疯了吗? -我保证马上还给你
- Have you lost your mind? - I'm gonna give it right back, I promise.
- 拜托, 兰德尔, 这真的很重要 -不, 兄弟  去坐下
- Please, Randall, it's really important. - No, bro. Go sit down.
- 请把戒指给我? -兰德尔, 别看他, 看我
- Give me the ring, please? - Randall, don't look at him, look at me.
兰德尔·兰德尔
Randall, Randall.
- 1秒  -把戒指戴在我手指上
- One second. - Put the ring on my finger.
- 不, 兰德尔, 听我说 -兰德尔! 看着我  我手上的戒指
- No, Randall, listen to me. - Randall! Look at me. Ring on my finger.
- 给我戒指! 只是一秒  -给它戴上戒指!
- Give me the ring! Just one second. - Put a ring on it!
亲爱的? 可以吗?
Please, love? Okay?
与这枚戒指…
With this ring...
-是的, 宝贝  -我很抱歉
- Yes, baby. - I'm so sorry about this.
-雪, 我的天  -哦, 伙计
- Snow, my god. - Oh, boy.
来了!
Incoming!
有人受伤吗?
Anybody hurt?
-索尼克! -夏威夷
- Sonic! - Hawaii.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
发生什么事情了? 摔疼吗?
What's happening? Are you hurt?
- 不, 不, 不, 我没事 -好吧, 好
- No, no, no, I'm fine. - Okay, good.
-这下你有大麻烦了! -好吧, 你冷静点
- Because you're in so much trouble! - Okay, you calm down.
你说话
You talk.
好的, 快速的版本
Okay, quick version.
机器蛋人回来了, 他在找魔法翡翠绿宝石
Robotnik is back on earth and he's after a magic emerald.
我们得把它拿回来, 不然世界就完蛋了
We need to get it back or the world is doomed.
尾巴
Tails!
-等等! 这一切都是昨天发生的吗? -等等, 尾巴是谁?
- Wait! All this happened since yesterday? - Wait. Who's tails?
尾巴, 你能听到我讲话吗?
Tails, can you hear me?
天啊, 现在有两个了
Oh, lord, there are two of them now.
好吧, 让我想想, 让我想想  尾巴, 快醒醒, 伙计
Okay, okay, let me think, let me think. Tails, come on, buddy.
嘿!
Hey!
兰德尔, 为什么你所有的朋友都有武器?
Randall, why do all of your friends have weapons?
沃卓斯基夫妇, 你们真该邀请我一起吃早午餐
You really should have taken me up on that brunch, Mr. and Mrs. Wachowski.
橄榄园的家伙吗?
Olive garden guy?
没事的, 各位, 我们是联邦特工
It's okay, everyone. We're federal agents.
你也是, 探员, 执行你的任务吧
You, too, agent. Go ahead.
你是说整个婚礼都是个圈套?
You mean to tell me that this entire wedding was a setup?
-瑞秋 等一下 -什么?
- Rachel, wait a minute. - What?
没错, 女士
That's correct, ma'am.
"鲶鱼行动"的每个方面全都是捏造出来的
Every single aspect of operation catfish was a complete fabrication.
鲇鱼行动?
Operation catfish?
这里每个人都是特工吗?
So is everyone here an agent?
你是特工吗?
Are you an agent?
该死的. .
Son of a...
那个花商也是特工吗? 那摄影师呢?
Was the florist an agent? How about the photographer?
给我脱毛的那个女人…
The woman who waxed my...
在水疗中心?
At the spa?
- 乔乔(小女孩)难道也是是特工吗? -瑞秋
- Is jojo an agent? - Rachel.
-什么? -瑞秋, 听我说
- What? - Rachel, listen to me.
我不想听! 我不要听!
I'm done listening! I am done listening!
我很抱歉, 我真的很抱歉
I am so sorry. I am so sorry.
我真的很对不起
I really am. I am so sorry.
不, 嘿, 不!
No. Hey, no!
放开他! 嘿!
Let him go! Hey!
索尼克, 坚持住
Sonic, hang on.
-冷静别这么做 -汤姆!
- Take it easy. It's not worth it. - Tom!
索尼克没有威胁性, 他是我们这边的人
Sonic is not a threat. He's on our side.
他是个不受控制的外星人
He's an uncontrolled extraterrestrial.
你协助教唆他的日子结束了
And your days of aiding and abetting him are over.
在直升机到达之前, 把他们关在酒店里
Secure them in the hotel until the chopper arrives.
你犯了个错误
You're making a mistake.
你等着, 混蛋特工!
Hold on, major a-hole!
今天是我的大喜日子,
This is still my day,
得有人给我解释清楚这到底是怎么回事!
And someone is gonna explain to me what the hell is going on here!
旧金山事件之后成立了一个全球特遣部队,
After the events in San Francisco, a global task force was created,
致力于保护我们的星球免受外星人的威胁
Devoted to protecting our planet from alien threats.
就在那一天, 国家守护单位诞生了
That day, guardian units of nations was born.
-G-U-N, 掏枪至于吗? -枪, 没错
- G-u-n. Seriously? - Gun, yeah.
听着, 保若护我们的星球不受机器人博士的伤害如何?
Look, what about protecting our planet from Dr. Robotnik?
机器人早就死了吧
Robotnik is dead.
不对, 他又回来了
You're wrong. He's back.
而你却把唯一能阻止他的人都带走了
And you just hauled away the only ones who could stop him.
听说机器博士人又回来了
Sounds like robotnik might be back in play.
如果是的话, 马上找到他
If he is, I want him found immediately.
取消我橄榄园五点的约会
And cancel my five o'clock at the olive garden.
-玛迪阿姨? -怎么了
- Aunt maddie? - Yeah.
索尼克和他的朋友丢下了这个
Sonic and his friend dropped this.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
我想和我未婚夫说句话
And I want to have a word with my fiance.
那个词就是"谋杀"
And that word is "murder. "
嘿, 来吧  你不能把我们留在这里
Hey, come on. You can't just leave us in here.
我的朋友受伤了! 他需要医生, 兽医!
My friend is hurt! He needs a doctor, a vet, anyone!
尾巴, 你得醒醒了, 伙计  快醒醒
Tails, you got to wake up, buddy. Please wake up.
一切正常
All clear.
好吧, 计划
All right. Game plan.
我进入酒店, 找到他们关押汤姆和索尼克的地方
I get inside the hotel and find where they're hiding Tom and Sonic.
好吧, 那我去找兰德尔, 好吗?
Okay. Then I find Randall, right?
然后我掐住他让他无法呼吸
And then I squeeze the breath.
我现在已经经历了很多了
I'm going through a lot right now.
- 让我自己来处理好吗? -当然当然
- So let me process this my own way, okay? - Sure, sure.
-没意见  -应该带本日记夹来
- No judgment. - Should've brought a journal.
好的
Okay...
好吧, 这是用来当武器的吗, 太可爱了
Okay. Is this meant to be a weapon? This is adorable.
尝尝这个, 兰德尔!
Take that, Randall!
你跑啊, 兰德尔!
Run, Randall!
好了啦!
All right.
- 我们马上就知道了结果了 -好吧!
- We're about to find out. - All right!
我们去找点乐子吧
Let's go kick some Booty.
瑞秋! 不, 瑞秋!
Rachel! No. Rachel!
马上
In a minute.
站住!
Stop right there!
拿家伙
Get the bag.
他会回来的, 对吗?
He's gonna come back down, right?
难说.
I don't know.
祝你好运
Good luck!
听着, 汤姆和索尼克肯定在里面
Look. Tom and Sonic have to be inside.
我要去收拾未婚妻了
I got a fiance to vaporize.
- 小心背后妹妹 -好的
- Watch your back, sis. - Okay.
兰德尔!
Randall!
我们找到她了, 行动
We got her. Move in.
好吧
Okay.
我不是故意的!
I did not mean to do that!
有什么烦心事吗, 探员?
Something bothering you, agent?
我只是对瑞秋做的事有点内疚, 先生
I just feel a little guilty about what I did to Rachel, sir.
别担心, 我们会送她一张礼品卡
Don't worry about it. We'll send her a gift card.
兰德尔! 现在, 我提议干杯
Now, I propose a toast.
一次完美的行动
To a perfectly executed operation.
长官, 我们遭到攻击
Sir, we're under attack.
兰德尔, 你老婆回来了!
Randall, wifey's home!
天啊, 瑞秋
Oh, my god. Rachel.
真是个好女人
What a woman.
你这个渣男
You no-good,
卑鄙, 肮脏, 谎话连篇. .
Lowdown, dirty, lying...
瑞秋 先听我说
Rachel, just listen to me.
只有变态的人才会骗别人去办假婚礼?
What kind of twisted sicko tricks someone into a fake wedding?
派对结束了, 新娘哥斯拉, 呆在那儿别动
Party's over, bridezilla. Stop right there.
你这个狗娘养的. .
You son of a...
- 你试试 -不!
- Have it your way. - No!
不!
No!
真令人失望, 兰德尔探员
Very disappointing, agent handel.
- 那是武器吗? -我不知道, 但实验鉴真假
- Is that supposed to be a weapon? - I don't know, but we gonna find out.
你今天惹的麻烦还不够多吗?
Haven't you caused enough trouble for one day?
我还没开始惹麻烦呢
I haven't even begun causing trouble.
地狱的怒火比都不上新娘的愤怒
Hell hath no fury like a bride scorned.
看来像是真的, 对吧?
Looks like it's real, huh?
别动, 就是这样
No. Right.
讲真的, 被击中会有多糟?
Be honest. How bad is it?
糟不到哪里去, 你被电击了, 不会有事
Not bad at all. You got tased. You'll be fine.
-我好冷 -你掉到我们的冰雕上了
- I'm so cold. - You landed on our ice sculpture.
起来
Get up.
就. .
Just...
就告诉我一次真相吧
Just tell me the truth, for once.
你和我之间还有有什么事是真实的吗?
Is there anything about you or about us that was real?
瑞秋, 看着我
Rachel, look at me.
在我遇见你之前, 我甚至不敢想象我有资格获得真正的幸福
Before I met you, I didn't think that I was even capable of real happiness.
但当你走进我的生活, 一切都改变了
But that all changed when you walked into my life.
结果我违反了卧底工作的第一条规则
And I ended up breaking the first rule of undercover work.
是什么?
Which is?
永远不要坠入爱河
Never fall in love.
- 玛迪 -我们要逃出去
- Maddie! - We're busting out of here.
你怎么通过守卫的?
How'd you get past the guards?
因为那只小狐狸包里有一些疯狂的武器
Because that little fox is into some crazy stuff.
打开了
Come on.
-我们走吧 -你真了不起
- Let's go. - You're amazing.
那些猫头鹰真傻, 它们真以为能把这地方藏起来
The owls were fools to think they could hide this.
发生什么了?
What's happening?
稍等片刻
Wait for it.
真棒, 我找到了!
Yes. Eureka!
我找到它了
I've found it!
索尼克
Sonic.
- 那是什么?  -一个大问题
- What is that? - A big problem.
罗盘指引机器人博士找到了绿宝石
The compass led robotnik to the emerald.
那肯定有几百英里远
That's got to be hundreds of miles away.
好了, 集合, 我们来想个计划
All right. Huddle up. Let's figure out a plan.
- 一起 -没时间了
- Together. - There's no time for that.
我是唯一一个能够尽快赶到那里的人
I'm the only one that can get there fast enough.
索尼克, 你一个人做不了这么大的事
Sonic, this is way too big for you to do by yourself.
你看到那边那只小狐狸了吗?
You see that little fox over there?
他穿越整个宇宙来见他的英雄(我)
He came all the way across the universe to meet his hero.
-然而他的英雄做了什么? -我差点害死他
- And what did his hero do? - I practically got him killed.
你知道吗? 你是对的
You know what? You were right.
我的责任降临了, 但我搞砸了, 我不是英雄
My moment came and I blew it. I'm no hero.
- 等等 -不
- Wait. - No.
我不会让任何人因为我而受到伤害
I'm not letting anyone else get hurt because of me.
趁现在还来得及, 我要把这事解决了
I'm gonna fix this while I still can.
索尼克!
Sonic!
索尼克, 等等!
Sonic, wait!
小心点, 小心点, 等等
Hold on. Hold on. Wait, wait, wait.
- 别动, 别动 -放轻松, 小家伙, 你受伤了
- Don't move. Don't move. - Take it easy, little guy. You're hurt.
但我们必须帮他, 你不知道他面对的是什么
We have to help him. You don't know what he's up against.
现在相信我们了?
You believe us now?
嘿, 鲍勃!
Hey, Bob!
玛丽亚, 你好吗?
Hey, Maria, how you doing?
我在练习舞步
Working on my moves.
保持绿色出行, 无需开车烧汽油
Just keepin' it green. No need to burn the fuel.
说到汽油燃料. .
Speaking of fuel...
门关了?
Closed?
感觉不太对劲
That doesn't seem right.
关闭
Close.
就这个
Yes.
改造, 改造  看看你
Makeover, makeover. Look at you.
不许动! 警察!
Freeze! Police!
天啊, 你的手像机器人, 你的手像机器人
Oh, my god, you got robot hands. You got robot hands.
-不是, 这是手套 -把手举起来手指张开!
- No, they're gloves. - Get 'em up. Now spread your fingers!
现在动起来! 挥动起来!
Now wiggle 'em! Wiggle your digits!
没错! 就像你刚刚指挥音乐剧那样
Yes! Like you just finished a big musical number.
非常好
Good.
你头上怎么有盏灯?
Why is there a light on your head?
因为我是这个周末的治安官, 伙计
'Cause I'm the sheriff for the weekend, pal.
水
Water.
为什么非得是水?
Why did it have to be water?
好吧, 你能做到
Okay, you can do this.
得足够快
Gotta go fast.
我不想这样毫无意义的死去
I don't want to die like this! It's derivative!
给爸爸让个路!
Make room for daddy!
两全其美
Two and two.
太好了, 我们还是两足动物, 差不多吧
Great! We're still bipedals, more or less.
洞里着火了!
Fire in the hole!
我已经解决了, 每隔七秒就有一个陷阱. .
I've solved it. There is a booby trap every seven seco...
那有点早
That was a little early.
真高兴它没把我的胡子刮掉
So glad it didn't cut off my mustache.
嘿, 小红球
Hey, little red wrecking ball.
我知道你很想戴上绿宝石,
I know you're dying to get your emerald on,
但是我们能不能注意一下周围的环境?
But can we be a little bit more mindful of our surroundings?
可以吗?
May I?
30英尺后左转
In 30 feet, turn left.
要聪明的做事情而不是光靠努力
Work smarter, not harder.
我的屁儿
My pelvis.
好了, 秘密寺庙, 让我们看看你有什么
Okay, secret temple, let's see what you've got.
不! 不! 不!
No, no, no! No!
不
No.
真棒!
Yes!
你已经到达目的地
You have arrived at your destination.
哇, 这里面还真有个空间
Wow. That really opened up the space.
真不敢相信它还有一堵坚不可摧的墙
I can't even picture it with an impenetrable wall now.
碎裂的感觉总是让人很爽
And the rubble is always a nice touch.
终于来了, 翡翠大师
At last. The master emerald.
终极力量
Ultimate power.
很快就会恢复秩序
Soon order will be restored.
这一切都是因为我们合作得井井有条
All because of what we have done together.
多么可贵的情谊啊, 纳克尔斯
Such a lovely sentiment, knuckles.
我觉我有点感动得掉眼泪
I think I feel a single tear forming.
可悲的是. .
Sadly...
你对我来说就是通往(软饼干歌手)演唱会的门票工具而已
You're as useful to me now as a backstage pass to limp bizkit.
搞定了
Nailed it.
这家伙为什么总是想搞破坏!
This guy is always trying to spoil a bad thing!
你们也来了? 走了很远的路对吧?
You guys are here, too? Took the long way, huh?
对你来说什么都是笑话吗?
Is everything a joke to you?
为什么你总是干涉我的使命?
Why must you constantly interfere with my destiny?
因为我的使命是保护我的朋友和家人
Because my destiny is to protect my friends and family.
我想我刚刚已经说过了(总爱搞破坏)
I think I just threw up in my mouth.
如果你想要翡翠宝石, 你得先过我这一关
And if you want that emerald, you're gonna have to go through me.
今天针鼹不留活口!
The echidna's taking no prisoners today!
索尼克有勇气, 但他会一败涂地他能活下去吗?
Sonic has heart, but will he lose the quill to live?
我不想和你打架, 但你没给我太多选择
I don't want to fight you, but you're not giving me much choice.
太简单了, 来吧
Too easy. Let's do this.
你为什么不站着, 光荣地死去?
Why don't you stand still and die with honor?
我想想
Let me think about it.
好吧, 我考虑了一下, 然后就放弃了
Okay, I thought about it and I pass.
你好啊, 美女
Hi there, beautiful.
你看起来很真实, 不是吗?
You're the real deal, aren't you?
我这一辈子都在找你, 你都去哪儿了?
Where have you been all my life?
说再见吧, 刺猬
Say goodbye, hedgehog.
纳克尔斯, 住手, 机器人在偷翡翠宝石
Knuckles, stop. Robotnik's stealing the emerald!
你当我傻吗?
What kind of fool do you take me for?
你只管转过去看
Just look.
我的了
Mine.
等等, 我们说好的, 你不能这样
Wait! That wasn't the deal.
你这可怜又天真的家伙
You poor, naive creature.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
一个厉害的智者, 在一英里外就应该看到这个结果
A more advanced intellect would have seen this move coming a mile away.
或者1. 6公里
Or 1. 6 kilometers.
但我一直相信你, 你是我的朋友!
But I trusted you! You were my friend!
对不起, 我突然觉得很好笑
I'm sorry. That just hit me funny.
让这成为我给你上的最后一课吧, 你这个愚蠢的太空豪猪
Let this be my final lesson to you, you dim-witted celestial skin tag.
朋友们. .
Friends...
开放的, 诚实的, 但也很脆弱
Are open, honest and vulnerable with each other.
也就是 x 的平方乘以 y 的斜边,
Which means x squared times the hypotenuse of y squared,
除以友谊的绝对价值, 等于. .
Divided by the absolute value of friendship, equals...
杜奇! (一张专辑)
Dookie!
噢, 不
Oh, no.
混乱就是力量!
Chaos is power!
快离开这里!
Let's get out of here!
纳克尔斯
Knuckles!
又是水? 拜托!
Water again? Come on!
- 你救了我 -别跟我说话我没心情
- You saved me. - Don't talk to me. I'm not in the mood.
你怎么能在我伤心的时候攻击我!
How dare you attack me in my hour of sorrow!
你为什么要救我?
Why did you save me?
因为你先救了我,
Because you saved me first,
很显然你就有了优先战术优势, 我却搞不懂为什么
Which clearly gave you a tactical advantage I do not understand.
这不是战术, 是我不能让你死
It wasn't a tactic. I couldn't just let you die.
为什么? 一见面我就想干掉你
Why? I've been trying to destroy you since the moment we met.
因为当英雄不是只顾着自己
Because being a hero isn't about taking care of yourself.
而是要懂得为他人承担
It's about taking responsibility for other people.
智慧之语, 一句古老的地球谚语吗?
Wise words. An ancient earth proverb?
不, 先生, 这是瓦乔夫斯基家族的名言
No, sir, that's a wachowski family special.
从一个坐小船的人那里得到的
I got it from a guy in a rowboat.
一个对我很重要的人(甜甜圈主人)
Someone who means a lot to me.
等等, 那是什么声音?
Wait a second. What's that sound?
只有刺猬索尼克才需要这么大的救助
Only Sonic the hedgehog needs rescuing this much.
那只狡猾的小狐狸!
That sly little fox!
来吧, 傻瓜, 我们还没输呢
Come on, knucklehead. We're not beat yet.
在山上, 你告诉我你失去了一切
On the mountain, you told me you'd lost everything.
就像我一样
The way I did.
但你看起来总是充满阳光, 自由自在
But you seem so hopeful and free.
无视失败, 你是如何做到迎难而上的?
How did you move forward despite failing again?
一次又一次的…
And again. And again. And again. And again.
好吧, 我没失败那么多, 但我不是一个人做的
Okay, I didn't fail that much. But I didn't do this all alone.
我找到了新的家庭, 新的朋友
I found a new family. New friends.
你也可以
And you can too.
你不会再孤单了
You don't have to be alone anymore.
你这握手是认真的吗?
Are you kidding me with that handshake?
我不想再玩游戏了, 伙计
I'm done playing games, pal.
你得告诉我, 我想知道
You're gonna tell me what I want to know.
我最后一次问你. .
And I am asking you for the last time...
你想在百吉饼上加点什么?
What would you like on your bagel?
我是不会告诉你的
I'm not telling you anything.
这是一个百吉饼模型
And that is a display bagel.
我真搞不懂你! 我是说, 我什么都试过了
I don't get it with you! I mean, I've tried everything.
当好警察, 当坏警察, 还当给你百吉饼的警察
I was good cop. I was bad cop. I was cop who offers you a bagel.
什么都没有, 就像. .
And nothing. It's like...
那是个作展示百吉饼模型, 哇
That is a display bagel. Wow.
博士, 你来了
Doctor, you're here.
是的, 我来了, 但我. .
Yes, I'm here, and yet i'm...
不全在这里
Not all there.
老大, 你还好吗?
Sir, are you feeling okay?
我非常好
I'm more than okay.
我升级了
I'm upgraded.
邪恶3. 0
Sinister 3. 0.
我的游戏升级了
My game is next level.
嗨
Hi.
我能闻到电波的味道
I can smell the electricity.
你闻起来像个小吃盘
You smell like a snack plate.
是啊, 这说得过去, 我今天喝了两杯
Yeah, that's fair. I had a couple today.
坐下
Sit down.
坐在椅子上
In the chair.
我什么都没做奇怪了
I didn't know.
他明明坐在椅子上, 而我没有
'Cause he, 'cause he was in the chair, so I didn't.
好吧
Okay.
老大, 我们有麻烦了
Sir? We have a problem.
-所有小队就位! -建立防线!
- All teams in position! - Set up a perimeter!
走! 走! 走!
Move! Move! Move!
哪有什么麻烦, 我信赖的仆人
Incorrectus, my trusty barnacle.
这么多年过去了,
After all these years,
我终于得到了. .
What I finally got...
一个答案
Is a solution.
-指挥官 -汇报情况
- Commander. - Status report.
机器人博士和斯通还和一个人质在里面, 人质可能是当地警方人员
Robotnik is in there with stone and a hostage. Possibly local pd.
我不是说他蠢但如果他是当地警察
I'm not saying he's dumb, but if he is local pd,
那这个镇子有大麻烦了
This town's in a lot of trouble.
-韦德 -韦德(多半是韦德)
- Wade. - Wade.
好吧
Okay.
摇滚新春系列, 我懂了
Rockin' that new spring collection, I see.
这不是糕点大王吗
Well, if it isn't the pastry king.
是甜甜圈领主
The donut lord.
真正的天才应该记得人家的名字
A real genius would remember the name of the guy.
如果你敢破坏青山, 我还会这么做的
And I'll do it again if you mess with green hills.
恭喜你暂时的优越感
Congratulations on your oh-so-temporary sense of superiority.
你完蛋了, 机器人! 你的一切机械已被我们扣押
You're finished, robotnik! We've taken everything.
你的实验室, 你的无人机, 甚至你的资金!
Your lab, your drones, your funding!
让我们看看你没有那些沙雕的机器人, 你还能有多强大
Let's see how big of a man you are without your silly little robots.
你想看看. .
Would you like to see...
我能成为多大的男人吗?
How big a man I can be?
欢迎来到新的秩序世界
Welcome to the new norm.
我的天啊!
My god!
博士, 带我一起走吧!
Doctor! Take me with you!
他把所有东西都拆了
He's taking everything apart.
像是在造什么东西
He's building something.
这阵仗只有一个原因
That can only be one thing.
翡翠宝石的力量很可怕
The fearsome power of the emerald.
如果那家伙把思想转变为现实能量, 我们就有大麻烦了
If that thing really turns thoughts into power, we are in big trouble.
机器人博士有很多坏念头
Robotnik has a lot of bad thoughts.
嘿, 索尼克, 你确定把
Hey, Sonic, are you sure it was a good idea.
纳克尔斯其实不是坏人, 只是失去了理智
Knuckles isn't really a bad guy. He's just a little mixed up.
我没有搞混淆!
I am not mixed up!
我有钢铁般的意志力, 而且我有很多优点不像某些人
I have steely focus. And I'm complex. And that's a lot for some people.
希望你不是还在因我开车撞你而生气
Hope you're not still mad I hit you with that car.
我就没有受伤啊
I was completely uninjured.
我要在你最意想不到的时候复仇, 臭狐狸
And my revenge will come when you least expect it, fox.
先生, 你真了不起!
Sir, you're magnificent!
谢谢你, 马屁精
Thank you, sycophant.
你的崇拜是应该的
Your admiration is inevitable.
我就知道!
I knew it!
就像绵花糖鬼(捉鬼敢死队)一样
Just like the stay puft marshmallow man.
"征服世界"播放列表…
World domination playlist.
撤退
Fall back.
撤退! 快! 撤退!
Fall back! Quick! Retreat!
我们要怎么打败这玩意儿?
How are we supposed to beat this thing?
我们得有计划
We need a plan.
纳克尔斯, 用你的力量. .
Knuckles, use your strength to...
就从飞机上跳下去了, 哇!
Jump off the plane. Wow.
好吧, 我们这样做, 第一步: 光电嘲讽机器人博士
Okay, this is what we're gonna do. Step 1: Light taunting.
第二步: 我也不知道
Step 2: I have no idea.
索尼克
Sonic!
不错的玩偶, 蛋人
Nice action figure, eggman.
有什么鸟用, 还不是跟个丑八怪一样站在那里
Does it do anything or just stand there looking ugly?
跟"水泡"一样, 这丫反复的来
Like a blister, he keeps coming back!
他在猎杀名单上l, 放个导弹, 做个选择
He's on the okay-to-kill list. Shoot the missiles. Make a decision.
我需要点时间, 先生, 我正在想办法如何操作这个
I need a moment, sir. I'm trying to figure out how to do this.
你有没有看说明书吗?
Did you even glance at a manual?
-不! -我来
- No! - I'll do it.
原谅我的闪电
Pardon my lightning.
你最好把自己关起来
You might want to ground yourself.
我要把它像辣椒罐头一样打开…
I'm gonna pop that thing open like a can of chili...
抓紧
Hang on!
-耶! -差一点
- Yeah! - Close one.
索尼克!
Sonic!
机器人!
Robotnik!
骗子!
Deceiver!
去死吧, 死蚊子
Die, mosquito.
我感觉到了
I felt that.
发生什么事了?
What just happened?
这是胡子捣碎机, 说明书上有写的
It's the stache masher. Right here in the manual.
快递返回给发件人
Return to sender.
斯通
Stone?
很好, 接下来, 就会有报道说, 工作环境不友好
Great. Next thing you know, there'll be a report about a hostile work environment.
刚刚已经是最好的攻击方式了, 但他毫发无损
Those were our best attacks, and they did nothing!
只要机器人有绿宝石, 我们就打不过他
We can't beat robotnik as long as he's got that emerald.
他太强大了
He's too powerful.
听着, 我们不够强大, 不能靠自己打败机器人
Look, we aren't strong enough to beat robotnik on our own.
但我们有三个人
But there's three of us.
你的力量, 你的智慧和我的速度
Your strength, your smarts and my speed.
一起, 这样我们才能赢
Together. That's how we win.
所以我们要一起在战场上叱咤风云
So we make our stand here on the field of battle.
成为一个团队
As a team.
没错
This is it.
这是我们的责任
This is our moment.
该战斗了
Time to fight.
不得不说, 实际上我没有计划
Bad time to say this, but I don't actually have a plan.
尾巴, 有什么主意吗?
Tails, any ideas?
我们得找到他的弱点
We have to find his weak spot.
我建议攻击它裆部
I suggest the groin.
什么? 不, 不!
What? No. No!
理论上, 没错的, 裆部是最脆弱的部位
Traditionally, yes, the groin is the weakest spot.
别再说"裆部"了
Stop saying "groin. "
刺猬!
Hedgehog!
小心!
Look out!
我知道他的弱点是什么, 是我
I know what his weak spot is. It's me.
我就是他的弱点!
I'm the groin!
想想, 我快速到那家伙的脑子里去
Think about it. I live rent-free in this dude's head.
如果我去激怒他. .
So if I go out there and rile him up...
他会把注意力集中在你身上, 把他自本体暴露出来
He'll focus on only you, leaving himself open.
刺猬, 你是一个勇敢而高贵的战士
Hedgehog, you are a brave and noble warrior.
光荣地死去吧
Go to your certain death with honor.
看来我们得学学你鼓舞人心的语言了, 伙计
We're gonna have to work on your pep talks, pal.
-是的   - 走吧
- Yeah. - Let's go.
好吧, 胡子
All right, mustache.
你想要我? 来抓我啊
You want me? Come and get me.
你不用告诉我"来"和"抓"
You don't tell me about coming and getting.
我正在来抓你得路上!
I am on the cutting edge of coming and getting!
来了, 来了
Coming, getting.
来了, 来了, 来了, 来了
Coming, getting. Coming, getting. Coming, getting.
你真的很重
You're really heavy.
那是因为我百分之百是个肌肉男
That's because I am one million percent muscle.
快跟上, 狐狸!
Faster, fox!
-快! 快! 大家退后! -快走, 就这样! 快, 快, 快!
- Go! Move, guys! Move back! - Let's go, that's it! Go, go, go!
-继续跑! -跑! 跑!
- Keep going! - Go! Go!
-不不! 停下! -停车!
- No, no! Stop! - Stop the truck!
汤姆, 这里发生了什么?
Tom, what happened here?
-你和我想的一样? -我们去找我们的孩子
- You thinking what I'm thinking? - Let's get our kid.
-我们需要你的卡车 -我们需要你的卡车!
- We need your truck! - We need your truck!
来! 抓!
Coming, getting.
计划是什么?
So what's the plan here?
你要造个大机器人房子? 给自己找个大机器人老婆?
You gonna build a big robot house? Get yourself a big robot wife?
我要奴役人类, 让他们效忠于我
I'm going to enslave humanity and force them to service my machines.
先是青山, 然后是宇宙
First, green hills. Then the universe.
然后是多元宇宙
Then the multiverse.
谁知道呢? 也许这就够了
Then who knows? Maybe that'll be enough.
还不够公开么?
Full disclosure?
你不会想呆在那儿的
You won't be there.
激光眼? 开玩笑呢?
Eye lasers? Really?
鼻涕火箭!
Snot rocket!
不, 不, 不! 不, 不, 不!
No, no, no! No, no, no!
这就放弃了?
Giving up already?
当你和比你大700倍的人打时, 就不那么强悍了, 是吧?
Not so tough when you're fighting someone 700 times your size, are ya?
你打不过我的!
You can't beat me!
我无所不知, 无所不能
I'm all-powerful! All-knowing!
全世界都看见了
All-seeing.
看来你的机器人出了点小故障
Looks like your fancy robot has a glitch.
是我吗? 那我呢? 我在这里
Is it me? What about me? I'm over here.
上面! 下面! 后面!
Up top! Down below! Behind you!
我在这里, 抱歉, 这里
I'm over here. Sorry! Over here.
太慢了!
Too slow!
-你不可能比我聪明 -又错过我了
- You can't outsmart me. - Missed me again.
我比你聪明多了!
I'm the outsmarter-er!
我没有比你聪明, 我只是分散注意力
I didn't outsmart you. I'm just the distraction.
机器人!
Robotnik!
我也是一个全息图
I am also a hologram.
不忠诚的
Disloyal.
" dis"是我的风格
"Dis" is how I roll.
我的翡翠宝石呢?
Where's my emerald?
不, 不, 不, 不! 不, 不, 不!
No, no, no, no! No, no, no!
电脑, 备用电源
Computer, auxiliary power.
翡翠宝石, 就在那里
The emerald. It's right there.
走开, 你这个垃圾!
Move, you hunk of junk!
我得拿到它
I have to reach it.
快, 快, 快
Come on, come on, come on.
他在那儿! 快! 快, 快, 快!
There he is! Go! Go, go, go!
不!
No!
抓紧你了, 索尼克
We got you, Sonic.
注意了!
Hold on!
-你们没事吧? -没事
- You guys okay? - Yeah.
天啊
Okay.
我拿到了翡翠宝石, 我们还是能打败他的
I got the emerald. We could still defeat him.
拜托, 拜托, 这东西怎么用? 我该怎么办?
Come on, come on. How does this thing work? What do I do?
什么情况?
What?
不, 不, 不, 不, 不! 不, 不, 不, 不!
No. No, no, no, no! No, no, no, no!
看看这个幸福的小家庭
Look at the happy little family.
你得离我远点, 我才是他要找的人
You have to get away from me. I'm the one he wants.
嘿
Hey.
我们哪儿也不去
We're not going anywhere.
我们是一家人
We're family.
家人团结在一起
And families stick together...
无论如何
No matter what.
我爱你们
I love you guys.
我们也爱你, 索尼克
We love you too, Sonic.
不!
No!
我抓住他了!
I got him!
我终于搞定他了!
I finally got him!
那是什么?
What was that?
都结束了, 送鸡蛋的.
It's over, egg-man.
过去的就让它过去吧, 你觉得呢?
What do you say we just let bygones be bygones?
我做了一些事, 你也做了一些事, 双方都有好人
I did some things, you did some things. There are good people on both sides.
当然是两个聪明的人
Surely two intelligent beings.
-加油伙计加油 -干掉他索尼克!
- Come on, buddy. Come on. - Get him, Sonic!
对, 干他
Yeah. Come on.
哦, 就这?
It's like that?
好吧, 我们不是朋友
Okay, we're not friends.
回见, 仇人!
Later, hater!
-索尼克! -伙计!
- Sonic! - Buddy!
等等! 你不能碰他!
Wait! You cannot touch him!
刺猬拥有翡翠的力量
The hedgehog holds the power of the emerald.
对不起, 他已经不是你以前认识的索尼克了
I am sorry. He is no longer the Sonic you once knew.
什么?
What?
你得试试这个
You got to try this.
好吧, 他依然是你们之前认识的那个索尼克
Okay. He is exactly the Sonic you once knew.
-啊哈 -啊哈
- Uh-huh. - Uh-huh.
索尼克!
Sonic!
放马过来吧, 伙计
Bring it in, bud.
能穿上蓝色的衣服真好
It's good to be back in blue.
金色的穿上也很有趣, 但蓝色更适合我
The golden god thing was fun, but blue has always been more my color.
你穿起来很好看
Looks good on you.
索尼克, 你是宇宙中最强大的英雄, 而你却放走他
Sonic, you were the most powerful hero in the universe, and you let it go.
为什么?
Why?
因为我还有很长的路要走
Because I still have some growing up to do.
-我还挺喜欢当孩子的 -你不是一般的孩子
- And I kind of like being a kid. - And you're not just any kid.
你是我们的孩子
You're our kid.
没错!
That's right.
-来吧 -抱抱
- Bring it in! - Yay. Hugs.
幸好我们上次没这么做, 不然你会被炸死的
It's a good thing we didn't do this before. You would've blown up.
你把它修好了
You fixed it.
我花了一辈子的时间来寻找这个
I've spent my whole life questing for this.
现在我拿到了
Now I have it.
现在我们也有了
Now we have it.
我们该怎么办? 接下来怎么办?
What do we do with it? What next?
曾经有两个英雄阶层
There were once two orders of heroes.
但他们都去了天上
But they have all passed on to the great battleground in the sky.
所以我们要建立一个新秩序, 我们三个
So we start a new order. The three of us.
这可不是轻松的任务
This is no light task.
我们必须发誓要用我们的力量来保护宇宙的安全,
We must make a vow to use our powers to keep the universe safe,
互相照顾
To watch out for each other.
我们的新部落
Our new tribe.
我明白了!
I know!
-来个碰拳 -好主意
- A power bump! - Good idea.
这是地球的习俗, 一个不可违背的承诺
It's an earth custom. An unbreakable promise.
这不错
Very well.
那就来个碰拳吧
A power bump it is.
碰拳!
Power bump!
今天真是青山打棒球的好日子
It's truly a beautiful day for baseball here in green hills.
今天的阵容很精彩
An exciting lineup today.
在投手位置是来自银河系的新秀
On the mound, rookie sensation from across the galaxy,
无敌尾巴
Miles "tails" prower,
面对着得是超级发电站纳克尔斯, 针鼹鼠
Facing off against the powerhouse, knuckles the echidna.
啊不知道为什么
I don't understand.
为什么我对敌人的球很愤怒?
Why am I angry at the enemy ball?
你不必愤怒
You're not angry.
你只需尽力击球, 然后跑到球垒
You just want to hit it as hard as you can and then run around the bases.
但如果我的任务在我所站的地方结束, 为什么还要跑呢?
But if my quest ends where I am standing, why run at all?
我受不了这家伙  我为什么要跟他一组
I can't with this guy. Why do I even try?
这只是个游戏, 我们在这里玩得开心就好
This is just a game. We're out here having fun.
只是找点乐子
Just having some fun.
乐子
Fun.
好吧! 给他点颜色看看, 尾巴!
All right! Give him the heat, tails!
希望你准备好接受我的超快球了
Hope you're ready for my fastball.
你的快球即将会被拿下
Your fastball will be dishonored.
你也一样, 狐狸
And so will you, fox.
-放松伙计们! -别想太多
- Easy, guys! - Don't think about it too much.
抬起你的胳膊肘, 眼睛盯着球, 然后把它放下
Just keep your elbow up, eye on the ball and give it a ride.
旅行? 去哪儿?
A ride? To where?
能量碰碰! (碰拳)
Power bump!
胜利是我的!
Victory is mine!
嘿, 不公平! 那不算
Hey, no fair! That shouldn't count.
一垒也是我的!
First base is also mine!
-我想那是我们唯一的球 -我已经征服了第二垒!
- I think that was our only ball. - I have conquered the second of the bases!
谁想吃冰淇淋?
Who wants ice cream?
把盖子打掉了
Knocked the cover off that.
-冰淇淋! -冰淇淋耶!
- Ice cream! - Ice cream, yeah!
我正在享受嗨皮! 什么是冰淇淋?
I am having the fun! What is ice cream?
是甜点, 如果你享受乐趣, 你一定会喜欢的
It's a dessert. If you like fun, you're gonna love it.
好吃, 甜点, 里面有葡萄吗?
Yum. Dessert. Does it have grapes in it?
不, 通常不会
No, not usually.
我为我们的小家伙感到骄傲
I'm proud of our little guy.
我真的很喜欢他的新朋友, 尤其是那个红色的
I really like his new friends, especially the red one.
-他让我笑死了 -挥杆也不错
- He cracks me up. - Heck of a swing too.
来吧, 狐狸, 我们的甜点之旅在等着我们
Come on, fox. Our dessert adventure awaits.
-干得好伙计们 -是啊
- Good job, guys. - Yeah.
你也是, 宝贝, 我们去吃冰淇淋, 来吧, 来吧
You too, baby. Let's go get some ice cream. Come on, come on.
我为你感到高兴, 伙计
I'm happy for you, pal.
你找到了你的同类, 能一起成长的完美朋友
Got your wingmen. Perfect friends to grow up with.
-来吧, 纳克尔斯 -我的胜利战车!
- Come on, knuckles. - My victory chariot!
我想我得到的远不止这些… 爸爸
I've got a lot more than that... Dad.
看谁先跑到卡车那里
Race you to the truck.
一, 二, 三, 开始!
One, two, three, go!
不, 别对我手下留情, 我要你尽全力
No, don't go easy on me. I want your best.
索尼克, 我刚听说他们有糖果屑
Sonic, I have just been told they have sprinkles.
冰淇淋和糖屑? 这就是你要去探索的
Ice cream and sprinkles? This is your new destiny.
真是一顿完美的晚餐, 来庆祝我击败你的一垒
What a perfect meal to celebrate my victory over you in base of ball.
-什么? -我是说你差点就打败我了
- What? - I mean, you barely beat me.
你从没被打得这么惨过
You've never been beaten so hard.
不能忘记这个
Can't forget this.
探员, 我想知道最新情况
Agent, I want an update.
还在搜索, 长官, 我们没有发现机器人的踪迹
Still searching, sir. We haven't found any sign of robotnik.
没有人能在次坠机中幸存下来
No one could've survived that crash.
他死翘翘了, 终于解脱了
He's toast. Good riddance.
真是被那个疯子搞得一团糟
What a mess that lunatic made.
长官, 还有件事
Sir, there's something else.
我们在机器人博士仓库里清楚数据时, 还发现了一些情况
When we were wiping robotnik off our database, we found something.
系统深处藏匿着大约50年前文件数据
A file buried deep in our system and dating back over 50 years.
-那是什么? -坐标, 长官
- What was it? - Coordinates, sir.
坐标? 什么坐标?
Coordinates? To what?
一个绝密性研究机构
A secret research facility.
是个秘密基地, 长官
It was a black site, sir.
有人费了很大劲把这个藏起来
Someone worked very hard to keep this hidden.
我的天啊
My god.
启动暗影计划
Project shadow.